A Guide to the University of Connecticut, Faculty Club Records 1970.0005
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
Faculty Club Records
1915-1968
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1970.0005
2.5 Linear Feet
The Faculty Club of the Connecticut Agricultural College was founded in 1915. It was established as a social organization open to "all male members of the several college staffs whose names appear in the catalog."
History
The Faculty Club of the Connecticut Agricultural College was founded in 1915. It was established as a social organization open to "all male members of the several college staffs whose names appear in the catalog." The chairman of the preliminary meeting was President Charl and W.L. Seate, Jr. was elected Club president at the organizational meeting on 13 October 1915. The president and secretary-treasurer were to be elected annually. The members of the Faculty Club met the second Tuesday of each academic year, with additional meetings to be called at the President's discretion. In 1929, the Club meetings increased to once a month.
The late 1950s and the 1960s were a period of crisis for the organization. Concerns over housing for the Club included comments on the needs of women faculty. By 1961, there were three faculty organizations on campus: the recently re-named Men's Faculty Club (formerly the Faculty Club), the Women's Faculty Club, and the University Club. The latter was open to both men and women.
The Men's Faculty Club resumed its old name in 1964-1965 as the Women's Club was disbanded, or was absorbed into the University Club. It was suggested that the Men's Faculty Club disband in the early 1960s, but the motion was defeated. The Club continued to exist into the 1968-1969 academic year, although for how long is unclear. The exact date of the Club's dissolution is uncertain as the Club records are incomplete.
[This history was based on the official minutes of the Club and from a letter to University Archives by Mr. Ahern in September 1970.]
Scope and Content
The collection includes minutes, membership records, correspondence, financial records and similar materials documenting the activities of the organization and its members from 1915-1968.
Arrangement
Series I: Administrative Records ( 1915-1967 )
Series II: Committee Records ( 1924-1968 )
Custodial History
The records of the organization for 1962-1963 were in Mr. Ahern's possession for some time, previous years had been in the possession of Mr. George Van Bibber, President from 1961 to 1962, before he forwarded them on to Mr. Ahern at an unknown date.
Acquisition Information
The records of the Faculty Club were transferred to Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center in 1970 by Thomas E. Ahern.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
College teachers; Societies; Universities and colleges; Administrative records; Correspondence; Minutes (administrative records); Connecticut (state); Financial Records; Fliers (printed matter); Notes; bylaws (administrative records); University Club (University of Connecticut); Women's Faculty Club (University of Connecticut); Men's Faculty Club (University of Connecticut); Faculty Club of the Connecticut Agricultural College.
- Series I: Administrative Records, 1915-1967
  - Articles of Association and By-Laws, circa 1915-1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes (Record Book), 1915-1931 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes (Record Book), 1931-1955 (Box 4)
  - Minutes, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes (Record Book), 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Financial Records, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Financial Records, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Financial Records, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Financial Records, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Financial Records (Checkbook receipts), 1956-1963 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Financial Records, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Financial Records, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Financial Records, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Financial Records, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Financial Records, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Financial Records, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Financial Records, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Financial Records, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Financial Records, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Financial Records, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Guest Register, 1951-1952 (Box 5)
  - University Club, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Series II: Committee Records, 1924-1968
  - Building, 1949-1951 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Children's Party, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Membership, 1924-1936 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Membership, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Membership, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Membership, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Membership, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Membership, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Membership, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 52-53)
  - Membership, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Membership, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Membership, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Membership, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Membership, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Membership, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Membership, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Refreshment, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 61)